我叫梅林达·戈登
My name is Melinda Gordon.
刚结婚  刚搬来这个小镇
I just got married, just moved to a small town,
刚开了间古董店
just opened up an antique shop.
我也许和你相似
I might be just like you.
但当我还是小姑娘时
Except from the time that I was a little girl,
我就能同亡者交流
I knew that I could talk to the dead.
没事的  亲爱的
It's all right, honey.
祖母称他们为地缚灵
Earthbound spirits, my grandmother called them,
他们在人间滞留
the ones who have not crossed over
因为他们有未了的心愿
because they have unfinished business with the living.
他们找我寻求帮助
And they come to me for help.
讲述我的故事  就是讲述他们的故事
To tell you my story, I have to tell you theirs.
不要调你的电视机
你现在听到的是超自然电子异象
俗称白噪声
服务员貌似没听懂你的幽默
You know, I don't think that waiter got your sense of humour.
是呀  因为他只顾着看你
Yeah, I think it's because he was looking at you so much,
根本就没听我说
he didn't even hear me.
你明天去车站接你妈吗
Are you gonna pick up your mom tomorrow at the train?
不  她坚持坐出租车
No. No, no. She insists on taking a cab, you know.
她从不轻易接受帮助
She likes to think she's low-maintenance.
我们不都一样
Ah, don't we all?
她总有自己的理由
She always has her reason.
怎么了
What?
我明明把车停在这里了
This is exactly where I parked the car.
你确定
Are you sure?
当然  我们差点被这裂缝给绊倒
Yeah. Remember? When we almost tripped over that crack there.
真不爽
I am not enjoying this moment.
晚上好  我车被偷了
Evening. I need to report a stolen car.
奥文顿大道415号  车主是梅林达·戈登
415, Ovington Avenue. Vehicle belongs to a Melinda Gordon.
动作真快  比利
That was quick work, Billy.
又没啥事儿  帮个忙而已
Hey, slow night. What can I say?
他在附近交通违规  被我们抓住
We caught him running a stop sign a few blocks away.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
差点冲进这家的草坪
Damn near drove right over the lawn of this house.
估计是飙车党
A joyride, I'm guessing.
一个人飙车吗
A joyride of one?
多次行为不端  但没有前科
He's got a couple of misdemeanours, no major priors.
你们准备怎么办
What you guys wanna do?
迈尔斯·詹森  男孩的父亲
Miles Jensen, the boy's father.
我为此向你们道歉
I really apologise for this.
我儿子正值逆反心理旺盛期
My son, he's in that troublemaker phase, I guess.
值得庆幸的是  没有人受伤
No one was hurt. That's all that matters.
我有个不情之请
I know this is asking a lot,
能否不起诉他
but would you consider not pressing charges?
我会赔偿一切损失
I'll pay for the damage.
可以
Sure. Yeah. It's okay.
万分感谢
I really appreciate that.
我不知道这孩子怎么了
I don't know what is with the kid.
真希望他能一觉醒来突然开窍
Sometimes I wish he'd wake up, be 21
别再这么不懂事
and have all this teen crap behind him.
亲爱的
Honey.
他把你的电台调乱了
He messed with your stations.
我们真该起诉他  调头回去
We should prosecute. Let's go back.
知道我怎么想吗
Hey, you know what my problem is?
我想一觉醒来能回到16岁
I need to wake up, be 16
不用管成人的烦心事
and get over all this adult crap.
等一下  靠边停一下
Hold on. Pull over for a sec.
这是手机信号  还是什么
What, are those cell phone transmissions? What?
恐怕不是
I don't think so.
我觉得这是灵魂的声音
I think these are spirit voices.
慢着  我是正常人  怎么能听见
Wait a minute. Normal guy. How come I can hear them?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
你怎么知道那是灵魂
How do you know they're spirits?
感觉  我能感觉到
I feel it. I can feel them.
怎么  车闹鬼了
What, the car's haunted?
我不清楚
I don't know.
我从没遇到过
I've never run into this before.
这现象还有个名字来着
There's a name for it.
酷  其实是毛骨悚然
Cool. I mean, creepy.
我在这
I am here.
鬼语者  第一季  第9集
灵异之音
有人吗  护理帅哥跑哪去了
Hello? Is there a handsome paramedic in this house?
你有4条留言
You have 4 messages.
您送来的衣服已干洗完毕
Your dry cleaning is ready.
是我  安德里亚
Hey, it's Andrea.
关于湖心小区的房屋销售  你说对了
You were right about the estate sale in Lakemont.
给我回电话
Give me a call.
吉姆  我是汤米
Jim, it's Tommy.
下周二能值4到12点的班吗
Can you take the 4:00 to 12:00 shift next Tuesday?
你没事吧
You all right?
你听见这个没
Do you hear that?
一点点  不知道是啥
Barely, but yeah. Don't know what it is.
没事吧
You okay?
还好  就是突然有点头疼
Yeah. Yeah, except for a headache all of a sudden.
好了
All right.
没事了
It'll be all right.
我妈刚到你就头疼  有意思
You get a headache, my mother arrives. Interesting.
亲爱的
Hey, darling.
见到你太高兴了
I'm so happy to see you.
我也是  妈  最近怎么样
It's great to see you, Mom. How you doing?
梅林达  亲爱的
Melinda, darling.
这个给你  谢谢
Hey. Here you go, man. Thank you.
-非常感谢  -吉姆
- Thanks very much. - Jim!
-怎么了  -你给小费那人是我朋友  埃利斯
- What? - You just tipped my friend, Ellis.
不好意思  埃利斯·康威
Sorry. Ellis Conway.
这是我儿子  吉姆
This is my son, Jim.
-你好  吉米  -你好
- Hiya there, Jimmy. - Hey.
还有我漂亮的媳妇  梅林达
And my beautiful daughter-in-law, Melinda.
梅林达  听说很多你的事
Melinda. Heard a lot about you.
见到你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
我还要去拿剩下的包  马上回来
Well, look, I got another bag to get. Be right back.
真体贴啊
Isn't he sweet?
他是谁
Who is he?
你知道的
Well, you know who.
我不知道
I don't.
他是...
He's my...
说男朋友太荒唐了  是不是
Well, boyfriend is just ridiculous, isn't it?
他是一位特别的朋友
He's a special friend.
男朋友  妈  你没说过
Boyfriend. Mom, you didn't mention this.
没有吗  梅林达  你真是美极了
Didn't I? Melinda, you look wonderful.
挚友  你也是楚楚动人
And you, Faith, you're just glowing.
妈...
Mom...
吉姆  别问了  我自会解释的
Jim, please don't be boring about this. I'll explain more later.
这房子真漂亮
What a fantastic house, gee.
-我来拿  -谢谢
- Yeah. Great. I got it. - Thanks.
亲爱的  这边走
Here, darling.
饿了吗
Anyone hungry?
饿极了
Yeah. Sure.
真是美味
This is yummy.
太棒了
Wonderful.
你应该先付钱的
Hey. You're supposed to pay for those.
先记下
Keeping track.
好吧  你和埃利斯怎么了
All right. What's up with you and Ellis?
我们怎么了
What about me and Ellis?
你俩没说过半句话
You haven't spoken two words to the guy.
没什么
It's nothing.
你看不惯他和你妈妈在一起吧
Does it bother you that him and your mom...
嘿  嘿  非得说穿吗
Hey, hey, hey. Do we have to put a name on it, huh?
真搞不懂  他看上去挺不错
I don't get it. He seems like a perfectly nice guy.
那他干嘛搭讪那金发女孩
Then how come he's checking out that blonde
而不是我妈妈
who is clearly not my mother?
吉姆  因为
Because, Jim,
那个金发女孩拿着甜点
that blonde is a Nordic goddess with huge pastries.
看一眼可不是什么罪过
A priest would be forgiven for glancing.
那可不是看  那是秋波  拜托
That's not a glance. That's a leer. Come on.
我不清楚  只是感觉有些不对
I don't know. It just... Something doesn't feel right.
你父亲去世后  你妈妈有约会过吗
Has your mom dated anybody since your dad passed away?
据我所知没有
Not that I know of.
那不就得了
Say no more.
不敢相信
I can't believe
你居然安排他们住不同的房间
you tried to put their bags in separate rooms.
我开玩笑的
I was kidding.
-他们是成年人了  -我总觉得
- They are adults. - I don't know.
那个埃利斯哪里不对劲
Something about this Ellis guy just doesn't seem right.
你知道他们怎么认识的吗
You know how they met?
他帮我妈安装新的警报系统
He was installing her new alarm system.
我觉得他很温柔很有魅力
He seems sweet and charming to me.
好吧  你喜欢就喜欢呗
Yeah, yeah, if you like that sort of thing.
到底怎么了
What is this really about?
我不知道  只是  你知道吗
I don't know. It's just... You know what it is?
他太好了  我不信他
He's too nice. I'm not buying it.
疑心病
Oh. Cynical.
我爸爸去世五年了
Dad's been dead five years.
他真是和我爸爸太不一样了
He's just... He's really different from my dad.
你要接受事实
You know, maybe you should just get used to the idea
你妈妈在谈恋爱
that your mother is dating.
-你怎么了  -没什么  又头疼
- Are you all right? - Yeah. Damn headache.
手给我  和上次一样的症状吗
Give me that. Is it the same as the ones before?
恩  留言机里又发出奇怪声音了
Yeah. There were weird voices again on the answering machine.
我听了两次  整晚都很难受
I listened to them twice and I've been sick all night.
不要再听了
Don't listen to them.
够男人  我喜欢
That is so male. I love that.
本色而已
It seems simple to me.
你肯定这现象无法解释吗
Look, are you sure these things aren't explainable,
-比如手机信号  -恩  没解释
- I mean, like cell phone transmissions? - No, they're not.
你知道我如何感知灵魂的吗
You know how I can sense spirits,
我能感受到他们的感受
like I can feel what they're feeling?
现在我超负荷了
Now I'm on overload.
就像一次吃得太撑了
It's like tasting too many foods at once.
我不愿见你为此难受
I don't like this is making you sick.
我去帮你拿阿司匹林
Should I get you some aspirin?
你知道治头痛的特效药是什么
You know what always makes my headaches go away?
当然
Oh, yeah.
等一下  别关门
Wait. Hold those doors.
请等一下  谢谢
Please. Thank you.
谢谢  你真好
Thanks. You're a pal.
帮我省了半小时
Probably saved me about a half an hour.
你去哪层
Which floor?
和你一样
Well, same as you.
你是要去找霍夫曼博士吗
Are you here to see Dr. Huffman?
-你怎么知道  -我通灵
- How did you know? - Psychic.
再说三楼只有他一间办公室
That, and there's only one office on the third floor.
这么说你就是霍夫曼博士
Which makes you Dr. Huffman.
你好像有点惊讶
You seem a little surprised.
没有  非常抱歉  只是
Oh, no. No. I'm sorry. It's just...
-打电话时觉得你会年长些  -哦
- You sounded older on the phone. - Yeah.
事实上我好几位女朋友
I've actually had a lot of blind dates
起初都这么说我
which began with that same phrasing.
我是梅林达·戈登
Melinda Gordon.
今早找你谈过我的留言信息
We talked this morning about my messages.
是的
Oh, yes! Of course.
超自然电子异像
Electronic voice phenomenon.
我们研究噪音的简称为EVP
EVP, as we noise geeks like to say.
对了  你对这东西了解多少
Well, how much do you know about it?
不多  就从网上看到过
Oh, not much. Just what I learnt on the net.
你的名字不断出现在搜索结果中
Your name kept coming up in my searches.
正是我要找的EVP专家
You seem to be the go-to guy for EVP.
协会主席可不这么认为
Yet the chairman of my department remains unimpressed.
要来点儿奶酪吗
Would you care for some cheese?
熏制的荷兰干酪
Smoked Gouda.
不用了  谢谢
Oh. I'm good. Thanks.
你大部分时间都在研究超自然现象吗
So do you mostly work in paranormal studies?
我不认为这是超自然
Well, I don't think of it as paranormal.
我试图用科学来解释
I'm simply trying to apply scientific explanation
这些不可解释的现象
to phenomena that seem unexplainable.
EVP现象很普遍吗
Is EVP common?
不好说  我们没做过统计
Hard to know. We don't exactly keep statistics.
大多数声音都传播于
Most of the voices seem to mostly come through
广播电台的空频带中
the vacant bandwidth between regular broadcast stations.
但它不仅出现在电台中
But it's not just radio, you know.
任何电子设备都有可能
It could happen with anything electronic.
包括电视  显示屏  录像机等等
TVs, monitors, VCRs, et cetera.
大多数人不知其所以然
Most people really don't know exactly how or why it works.
所以认为是鬼魂发出的
Most people believe it's caused by ghosts.
-你相信鬼魂吗  -你呢
- Do you believe in ghosts? - Do you?
我若如实回答
I'd answer that truthfully,
估计会掉饭碗
but I may be endangering my tenure.
这么说吧  我比较开明
Let's just say I... I like to keep an open mind.
-你说收到几条留言  -是的
- Now, you said you have messages. - Oh. Yes.
那声音在其它留言之后
The voices are hidden under my other messages.
我在车载广播里也听过  给你
And I'm also hearing voices on my car radio.Here.
还好你没吃奶酪  难吃死了
Good call on the cheese, by the way. It's dreadful.
我都被弄疯了
It's just been driving me crazy
完全不明白说的是什么
that I can't understand what's being said.
看  这有很多音频变形  看这儿
See, there's a lot of warping. Watch this.
非常典型
Very typical.
大部分的声音像是在谈话
Most of the voices seem to be in mid-conversation,
一部分是在提问
some asking questions.
突然有个女人的声音
There's one female voice which seems to pop.
她好像不是在谈话
She doesn't seem to be in conversation
像是想让别人听她说话
as much as trying to get someone to hear her.
你看上去不太舒服
You suddenly seem unwell.
不  我没事
No, I'm good.
你能告诉我他们在说什么吗
Can you just tell me what they're saying?
我在
I am...
我在等
I am waiting...
我在等你
I am waiting for you.
你认为是这声音让你不舒服吗
And you think these voices are making you sick?
跟声音没什么关系
It's not so much the voices.
只是一次出现太多鬼了
It's just a lot of spirit stuff happening all at once.
我的头都震痛了
I feel like my head's vibrating.
你面色有些苍白
You are looking a little green around the gills.
你的面色也不错
You look good, too.
你为什么不回家休息
Why don't you just go home?
店里的事我能应付
You know, I can handle things here.
别傻了  我好得很
Don't be ridiculous. I'm fine.
克莱蒙在树丛里
Claremont in the woods.
克莱蒙是谁
Claremont?
抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry. I have to go.
克莱蒙小径
现在怎么办
Now what?
你是谁  来这干什么
Who are you? What are you doing here?
我是谁
Who am I?
我是被你偷过车的那位
I'm the woman whose car you stole.
你应该对我礼貌些
And you should try being polite.
要谢谢我没把你送进监狱
Thanks to me, you're not stuck in jail right now.
回答我的问题
Answer my question.
你先回答  你来这干什么
You first. What are you doing here?
我在散步  这是天然小径
I'm walking. It's a trail, man.
你也是被引到这来的吗
Were you led here, too?
你在说什么  谁会引我到这
What are you talking about? Led here by who?
有人告诉我到这来
Someone told me to come here.
一个女人  她也告诉过你吗
A woman. Did she tell you, too?
你也听到那声音了是吗
You hear the voices, too, don't you?
你
You're...
你这疯子
You're nuts, okay?
我不知道你胡说八道些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你不必这样  我睡一觉就好了
You don't have to do this. I'll feel better in the morning.
当然要做  反正我也睡不着
Of course I do. I can't sleep anyhow.
别告诉我  你在烦你妈的事
Don't tell me you're obsessing.
如果他是骗子怎么办
What if he's a gold digger?
如果他看上我妈的钱怎么办
I mean, what if he's just after her money?
你希望门当户对是吧
This is a class thing, isn't it?
我以为你了解我
I think you know me better than that.
拜托  承认吧
Come on, admit it.
你觉得他配不上你妈
You don't think he's good enough for your mother.
不是的
It's not that.
那是怎样
What then?
我认为他配不上我妈
I don't think he's good enough for my mother.
感觉好点了吗
Feel better?
我早就好了  刚才都是装的
I felt better hours ago. I've been totally milking it.
乖宝贝
That's my girl.
我能问你个问题吗
You know... Can I ask you a question?
你跟那么多鬼魂对阵过了
You've been through a lot with this whole spirit game, right?
你也是
We both have.
没错  但我从没见过哪个能让你不舒服
True enough. But I've never seen it make you sick before.
不必小题大做
Don't make it bigger than it is, you know.
只不过这次失控了
I just can't get control of this one.
我觉得  这不是好事
My point. It's a bad thing.
你有没有想过  也许你能说
Look, do you ever think there'll be a day where you can say,
对不起  我帮不了你
you know, "Sorry. I can't help you.
你对我有害
"You're not good for me.
你让我不舒服  让我流泪
"You're making me sick. You're making me cry"?
会有这么一天吗
Do you think that day will ever come?
我不知道  该有吗
I don't know. Should it?
我去楼下倒杯水
I'm gonna go downstairs and get a glass of water.
你要些什么
You want anything?
智慧和耐心
Wisdom and patience.
那可是抢手货
Always in short supply.
我就拿些椒盐饼干来吧
Saltine crackers are gonna have to do and those are for me.
让他听
Make him listen.
你是谁
Who are you?
让他听
Make him listen!
还有谁的声音
Who are the other voices?
你在场  却什么也没做
You were there. You did nothing!
我在等待
I'm waiting...
怎么回事
What's going on?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事了  你还好吗
It's all right. You all right?
-抱歉  -没事了  没事了
- I'm sorry. - It's all right. It's all right.
拜托
Come on.
回去  回去
Go back. Go back.
你想告诉我什么
What are you trying to tell me?
我的儿子
My son.
他在哪里  你一定要告诉他
Where is he? You've got to tell him.
该死的  我忘记给你赔偿的支票了
Damn. I forgot to send the cheque for the car.
我现在就开给你
You know, I can do that right now.
不用  保险公司赔了
No, no, no, no. The insurance company's taking care of it.
我只是顺路来看看柯克
I just wanted to come by and check on Kirk.
柯克
Kirk.
是的  看看他近况如何
Yeah. Just see how he's doing.
你说过你们不会起诉他的
You said you weren't going to press charges.
当然不会
Honestly, I'm not.
我只想  和他谈谈
I just, I don't know, wanted to talk to him.
安抚一下他的心情
You know, make sure there was no hard feelings.
你是社工吗
Are you a social worker or something?
我做了不少公益  不过我不是
I get that a lot. Not really. No.
那好  谢谢你的关心
Well, it's nice of you to take an interest.
但是他不在这  再也不住这了
But he's not here. He's never here.
他去哪里了
Where does he go?
我也不清楚他去哪了
I'm not privy to that information any more.
就你们二人吗
It's just the two of you?
什么
Excuse me?
我只是好奇
Oh, I was just wondering.
我妻子过世了  你是不是要问这个
My wife passed away, if that's what you're asking.
我儿子一直是个好孩子
You know, my son was a good kid until then.
成绩优秀  生活幸福
Made good grades. He was happy.
他母亲过世后  他就开始吸毒和惹事
When his mother passed away, he just spiralled.
不久就沾上了毒品等恶习
All of a sudden, it was drugs and petty crime.
他对谁都不说一句话
You know, he doesn't say a word, not to me or anyone else.
相信我  我尽力了
And believe me, I try.
我真的尽力了
I really try.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
算了  我要赶飞机了
Anyway, I got to catch a plane.
好吧
Right.
对不起  请留步
Hey, I'm sorry to hold you up.
我能留张名片吗
Can I just leave a card?
万一他想找人谈谈呢
You know, just in case he does wanna talk.
你是社工  是吧
You are a social worker, aren't you?
也许你说对了
Maybe you're right.
行  他确定我走后也许会回家的
Go ahead. He'll probably come home when he's sure I'm gone.
抱歉
Excuse me.
她母亲是怎么死的
How did his mother die?
是场意外  她死在了树林里
It was an accident. She died in the woods.
去找红...
Find the red...
去找红手套
Find the red glove.
红手套
Red glove.
去找红手套
Find the red glove.
红手套
Red glove.
-比利  -吉米
- Billy. - Hey, Jimmy.
你来培训的吗
Doing a training thing here or something?
-不  能跟你谈谈吗  -行  边走边说
- No. Actually, can I talk to you? - Yeah, sure, come on.
你不是想拿我练海姆立克急救法吧
You're not gonna try to Heimlich me or something, are you?
算你运气好  放过你
Maybe if you're lucky, next time.
什么事  兄弟
What you need, baby?
听着  我是无事不登三宝殿
Look, I wouldn't ask you this if I wasn't...
怎么了
What?
我妈跟一个男人在约会
Well, my mom started seeing this guy.
不知为何  我总觉得他怪怪的
And I don't know. Just got a weird feeling about him.
怎么个怪法
Weird how?
说不上来  比利
I don't know, Billy.
我想让你帮我查查他的底细
I was just wondering if you could run a check on him.
他住在费城
He lives in Philadelphia.
费城
Philadelphia.
我不太清楚能查到些什么
I don't know what I can get from here.
查查车管局  找找庭审记录
Maybe DMV. Maybe some court records.
我碰碰运气吧
It'd be a shot in the dark.
无论结果怎样  感激不尽
I'd appreciate anything you could do.
好吧  那么...
Okay, well...
你们怎么了  减薪了吗
What's wrong with you guys? Cutbacks?
-他叫什么  -埃利斯·康威
- What's his name? - Ellis Conway.
是个电工  费城人
He's an electrician. Philadelphia.
有意思  他总对挚友的男朋友疑神疑鬼
Oh, it is so cute. He's all twitchy about Faith's boyfriend.
谢谢
Thank you.
但他看上去人不错啊
He seems like such a nice guy.
没错  他的确如此
Oh, he is. He really is.
但她可是吉姆的妈妈
But, you know, it's Jim's mom,
他一定会替她把关的
And he's always gonna look after her.
毕竟她有点感情用事
She's a little impulsive.
真好  我喜欢感情用事的人
Oh, that's great. I love impulsive.
喂  等等
Hey! Stop!
你好
Hi.
我能帮你
你能让这声音消失吗
Can you make this stop?
红手套
Red glove.
你觉得是谁的声音
Who do you think it is?
不管是谁  我只想让它消失
I don't care who it is. I just want it to stop.
是你妈妈  对吧
It's your mother, isn't it?
你妈妈是干什么的
What did your mother do?
她是电气工程师  设计电路板
She was an electrical engineer. Designed circuit boards.
那又能说明什么
What difference does that make?
说明她非常精通电子
So she knew a lot about electronics.
应该吧
I guess.
灵魂摄取人的能量才能表达意愿
Spirits need our energy to manifest.
她死在树林里
She's out in the woods.
那里没有她可利用的能量
There's no one there for her to draw on.
于是她就试图利用
She's probably trying to communicate
唯一熟悉的东西进行交流
On the only thing that's familiar.
你怎么知道这些
How do you know all this?
我有这本事  能跟灵魂打交道
It's what I do. The spirit part, anyway.
我觉得你妈妈想向你传达某种讯息
Look, I think your mother's trying to get a message to you.
她在树林里等着你
And she's there. She's waiting for you.
我不想听她的任何讯息
I don't want any messages from her.
我只想让这声音消失
I just want the voices to stop.
你说能帮助我  帮我啊
You said you could help me, so do it.
你知道红手套的事吗
Do you know anything about a red glove?
我妈妈是个骗子
My mother's a liar.
无论她是生是死  都跟我毫不相干
I don't want anything to do with her, living or dead.
当时在树林里到底发生了什么
What happened to you in these woods?
那天  秋高气爽  风和日丽
An autumn day. Beautiful sun.
一切都如此舒适  如此惬意
Everything felt so good, so right.
我仿佛重回少女时代  自由自在
Free. I felt like a girl again.
他为我带来了这一切
He did that for me.
我们已相识多年
We met years ago.
我们当时只是好友
We were friends, that's all.
但我的婚姻冷若冰霜
But my marriage was so cold,
是鲍勃让我有了爱的感觉
And Bob made me feel loved.
我轻轻地摔了一跤
It was just a little fall.
一点都不疼
Didn't hurt.
坑里有一条裸露的输电线
There was a broken power line at the bottom of the well.
我触电了
I had been electrocuted.
莱西
Lacy!
我还来不及求救就已死了
I was dead before I could even yell or shout out.
救命  救命
Help! Help!
我该如何解释
How could I explain?
我儿子柯克信任我  他永远不会理解的
My son Kirk trusted me. He would never understand.
后来消息就传开了
That's when everybody knew.
-什么消息  -我们是情人
- Knew what? - That we were lovers.
我们有婚外情
We were having an affair.
我的家庭土崩瓦解
My family was devastated.
每个人都无法容忍我的背叛
And everyone felt betrayed.
连我儿子柯克也对我丧失了信任
Even my son Kirk lost faith in me.
他很愤怒
He was so angry.
他开始荒废自己的天分
He started wasting his talent.
他的父亲呢
What about his father?
迈尔斯根本不理解
Miles doesn't understand.
不理解什么
Doesn't understand what?
红手套  他根本不知道...
The red glove. He doesn't know that...
红手套
Red glove.
你好  这里是詹森家  请留言
Hi. This is the Jensens. Leave us a message.
你好  柯克  还是我梅林达·戈登
Hey, Kirk, it's Melinda Gordon again.
我想和你谈谈  五分钟就好
If I could just talk to you for, like, five minutes.
真的很重要
It's really important.
请回电到我店里或打我手机
If you could just call my store or my cell.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还好吧  看上去很焦虑
Hey. Are you okay? You look worried.
对  我已经习惯这种焦虑了
Yeah. I guess I'm always worried about something.
你切这些  其它的交给我
Here. You chop these, and I will take care of the rest.
真有趣  我从未回家吃过午饭
This is fun. You know, I never come home for lunch.
总算知道吉姆为何厨艺精湛了
Now I know why Jim's such a good cook.
跟你说实话吧
To tell you the truth,
反而是我从他身上学到的更多
I learnt more from him than he did from me.
他对烹饪一直有着浓厚的兴趣
He has always been interested in food.
希望他至少能给埃利斯留点面包屑
Let's hope he gives poor Ellis a few crumbs at least.
你为此而困扰吗
Does it bother you?
我料到他会如此
It's what I expected, pretty much.
他的保护欲很强
He's very protective.
但他会想通的  埃利斯能征服所有人
But he'll come round. Ellis can win anybody over.
不得不承认
You know, I have to admit.
我羡慕你和吉姆的母子情
I envy what you and Jim have.
真希望我和我母亲...
I wish that my mother and I...
千万别这么说
Whoa. Careful what you wish for.
不容易啊  特别是他的成长期
It's not easy, especially the growing-up part.
我都记不清有多少次
I can't even count the number of times
我们互相大发雷霆
We were furious with each other.
现在也会
Still happens.
但他知道  有个人永远支持他
But he always knew someone had his back.
有个人永远都理解他
He always knew someone was out there who understood him.
你和吉姆母子情深
Well, you and Jim have quite a bond.
永远不会改变
Nothing's gonna change that.
得让他明白埃利斯没想改变这点
Now we just have to make him see that Ellis isn't trying to.
真迅速
That was fast.
如果是我妈妈  我也会很快
Hey, if it was my mom's, I'd be fast too, now.
-我请你喝咖啡  -不不不  我还有事
- Can I get you a coffee? - No, no, no. Look, I got to run.
-好吧  查到多少  -很多  看起来不妙
- All right, what do you got? - Plenty, and it isn't good.
还有什么需要  尽管给我打电话
Look, you call me later if there's anything else you want me to do.
-谢谢  比利  欠你个人情  -小意思
- All right, Billy, thanks. I owe you one. - Hey, no problem.
儿子
Son.
我爱你
I love you.
求你了  别再折磨自己
Please, stop hurting yourself.
妈妈
Mom.
求你了  别再折磨自己
Please, stop hurting yourself.
-我爱你  -妈妈
- I love you. - Mom!
求你了  别
Please! No!
-又是你  -柯克在吗
- You again? - Is Kirk here?
你可真会挑时间
You have amazing timing, I'll give you that.
怎么了
What's wrong?
欢迎来看我儿子最新的犯罪闹剧
Welcome to my son's latest crime spree.
他刚闯入了一家电器商店
He just broke into an electronics store
把那里弄得翻天覆地
and trashed the place or something.
我能帮上什么忙吗
Oh, is there anything I can do?
他像是专挑我最忙的时候
You know, it's almost like he waits until he knows I'm at my busiest
才来给我惹祸
before he pulls this crap.
我认为这与你无关  詹森先生
I doubt that it has anything to do with you, Mr. Jensen.
那你告诉我  这事关系什么
Well, please, tell me, what is it about?
他因丧母而伤心欲绝
He's grieving. He lost his mother.
我也丧妻了  那可谓釜底抽薪啊
I lost,too.Talk about having the rug pulled out from underneath you.
我已竭尽全力养育那孩子
You know, I've done my best for that kid.
我教他做男子汉  要坚强
I taught him to be tough, with a thick skin.
不然如何在这世上生存
How else can you survive in this worid?
他倒好  就会用垃圾桶砸店铺窗户
Instead he throws garbage cans through store windows.
詹森  你家门
Oh, Mr. Jensen, you left your door...
没关
...open.
就在这里  过来
Right here. Come.
找出来
Find it.
在这里找
Find it here.
红手套
Red glove.
应该就在下面
Underneath, where it should be.
床垫
Mattress.
红手套  找出来
Red glove, find it.
《红手套》  作者:柯克·詹森
抱歉  我能和我儿子单独谈谈吗
Excuse me, can I have a moment? It's my son.
谢谢
Thanks.
你为什么这么做  你昏头啦
Why are you doing this? I mean, is it that bad?
我说过  再惹事就送你去看心理医生
I told you I'd send you to a psychiatrist or a counsellor.
也许你真对谁敞开过心扉
Maybe if you actually talked to somebody.
可你不能再这样堕落了
But you can't keep doing this.
那你找个人来让我敞开心扉啊
Well, you let me know when you find me somebody to talk to.
好了  孩子  跟我走
All right, son, let's go.
谢谢
Thank you.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
他们说没人保释你
They told me no one's bailed you out.
对  他要给我教训
Yeah. He's teaching me a lesson.
只有在美景镇监狱受会儿罪
Nothing like doing some hard time in the Grandview jail
才能让浪子回头
to turn a guy around.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没关系  至少我能安心睡一晚
It's fine. At least I'll get a good night's sleep.
他们这里不让用电
They don't allow anything electronic in here.
我知道母亲的遭遇了
I know what happened with your mother.
你怎么知道
How?
她告诉我的
She told me.
对  好  随便
Yeah, okay. Whatever.
她知道你对她很生气
She knows how angry you are at her.
我不信
I doubt it.
是人都会犯错  她为此内疚不已
People make mistakes. She feels badly.
她应得的  她骗了我
She should feel bad. She lied.
我知道她为何要骗我爸
I know why she had to lie to my old man.
但为什么连我也要骗
But why did she have to lie to me?
我对她毫无保留
I told her everything about myself.
她不爱他  也许她也不爱我
She didn't love him. Well, maybe she didn't love me, either.
你知道她爱你
You know that's not true.
有时他人的所做所为  我们无法理解
Look, sometimes we don't understand why people do what they do.
每个人都有其苦衷
Everybody fights their own battle.
而我们却不知道
We may not even know what that is.
你从哪弄来的
Where the hell did you get this?
她引导我找到的
She led me to it.
你知道里面内容吗
You know what it's about?
讲的是一个年轻人不知如何
It's about a young man who doesn't know
开口告诉他爸  他是同性恋
how to tell his father that he's gay.
别以为保释我出来就能弥补你的过错
Bailing me out doesn't make up for what you did.
对我而言可以弥补
Maybe to me it does.
你无权阅读这份稿子
You had no right to read this.
写得很美  我都感动得哭了
It was beautiful. It made me cry.
显然这是性情中人所写
And it was obviously written by somebody with a great heart.
你该继续写下去
You should keep writing.
关你什么事
Look, it's none of your business.
你算哪根葱
Who the hell are you anyway?
为什么非得卷进这事
Why are you even involved with this?
因为你偷的是我的车
Because it was my car you chose to steal.
也许那是命中注定
And maybe that was no accident.
你爸知道你写作吗
Does your father know that you write?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
为什么不告诉他
Well, why not?
他不会理解  你也不会
He wouldn't understand, and neither do you.
谢谢你保释我  钱我会还你
Look, thanks for the bail. I'll pay you back.
谢谢你爸
Thank your father.
是他许可我接你出来的
He was the one that gave me permission to pick you up.
太好了  我该走了
Fantastic. I'm out of here.
账单  先生
Check, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
本以为这里的意大利菜不咋的
I was sure I wouldn't get any good Italian food out here.
我错了  不用  我来付
I was wrong. No, I got it.
你话不多  吉米  我欣赏你这点
You're a man of few words, Jimmy. I admire that.
你做电工多久了  埃利斯
How long have you been an electrician, Ellis?
电...
Electric...
我干这行十四五年了
Well, I've been in the business a good 14, 15 years now.
真的吗  没有其它副业吗
Really? Ever done anything on the side?
副业
On the side?
我一天到晚忙不停
I keep myself busy enough.
不见得
I bet you do.
我没听懂你的意思
I don't think I get you.
空头支票  网上诈骗
Writing bad cheques, Internet scams,
电话欺诈
telephone fraud.
我妈知道你在联邦监狱呆过两年吗
My mother know you spent two years in a federal prison?
你查我  吉姆
You checking up on me, Jim?
我是在查你  埃利斯
I'm checking up on you, Ellis.
能让我看看吗
May I see that?
就知道
Right.
你看   问题出在这里
Well, you see, a problem here.
我是叫埃利斯  但那是中间名
I go by "Ellis," but that's my middle name.
我本名是  文森特·文尼·康威
My real name is Vincent Vinny Conway.
你说的这个埃利斯·康威不是我
This here "Ellis Conway," that's somebody else.
你可以让你的朋友
So, why don't you go back to your guy
去查一下文森特·埃利斯·康威
And you give him the name "Vincent E. Conway,"
看看他做过什么
See what he comes up with.
你知道吗  吉米  你妈妈给我提过醒
You know, Jimmy? Your mother warned me about you.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute.
这么说  你改名字了
What? So, what, did you change your name or something?
我没改  只是扔了一个名
I didn't change it. I just dropped it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我刚开始工作时
Look, when I got my business started,
我觉得埃利斯这名字能提高身价
I thought going by "Ellis" would make me sound more high-class.
你知道的  有些人很在乎这个
You know how narrow-minded some people could be about these things.
吉米  我理解你  是真的
Look, Jimmy, I understand. I do.
我们都知道你妈妈非常好
Your mother's a wonderful woman. We both know that.
但她的心受过伤  迷惘过  很容易再受伤
But she's been hurt, she's lost, she's vulnerable.
你一直在照顾她  这也是我欣赏你的地方
You're looking out for her. That's something else I admire.
埃利斯  我不知该如何向你抱歉
Ellis, I don't know where to begin to apologise.
没关系  我自己也经历过很多事
Forget it, huh? I've been through a few things myself, you know.
生意时好时坏  妻子撒手人寰
Ups and downs in business. First wife passed away.
每个人都有自己的苦痛  对吧  孩子
Yeah, we all have our wounds, kid. Right?
我真想好好惩罚自己一下
Not as big as the one I'd like to inflict on myself right now.
我是没受过好的教育
I may not be a college guy,
但我做过不少正确的选择
But I've made some good moves in my time.
遇见你妈妈就是其中之一
Meeting your mom was one of them.
来点冰激凌吗
Hey, wanna go get some ice cream?
我们去吃点冰激凌
I say we get some ice cream.
走吧  去吃冰激凌  你请客
Then let's go get some ice cream. And you can pay.
难以置信  你竟然保释了那孩子
I can't believe it. I can't believe you bailed the kid out.
我怎能眼睁睁地看他蹲监狱
I couldn't just let him sit there in that cage.
没花多少钱  你生气了吗
It didn't cost that much. Are you mad?
生气  让我想想
Mad? Let me see.
我自信爱你足够深了
Just when I think I can't possibly love you more,
你却让我更爱你了
You prove me wrong.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine
要对一个本该无条件爱你的人
having to keep a secret like that from the one person
隐藏这样一个秘密
who's supposed to love you no matter what?
说到秘密...
Speaking of secrets...
奥文顿大道415号
415  Ovington
柯克
Kirk.
我好想记得这地方
How do I know that address?
警察的报告
It was on the police report.
那孩子偷我们车所去的地方
That's where the kid took our car when he stole it.
-你干吗  -当然是和你一起去
- What are you doing? - I'm coming with you. Are you kidding?
大半夜我们同时出去  邻居会起疑的
We can't both leave in the middle of the night.It'll look weird.
有事会给你打电话的
I'll call you if I need your help.
快点
Hurry!
我不会有没事的
I'll be fine.
你来这儿干什么
Hey, what are you doing here?
这是他住的地方
This is his house.
这才是我妈向往的地方
This is where my mother really wanted to be,
陪她的情人
with her lover.
别这样  跟我说说怎么回事
Come on. Don't do this. Just talk to me.
别担心  他不住这里了
Don't worry. He doesn't live here any more.
她的真爱  已经搬走了
The man my mother really loved, he moved away.
她知道你有多生气
She knows how mad you are at her.
她知道外遇这事伤你很深
She knows how much the affair hurt you.
但不仅如此  对吗
But it's not just that, is it?
她说你受的伤害超乎你的想象
She says you hurt even more than you know.
是吗  超乎我的想象吗
Really? More hurt than even I know? Wow.
真痛苦啊
That's a lot of hurt.
你痛苦是因为只有她
And you hurt because she was the only one
能够理解你  支持你
Who could possibly understand you. She had your back.
这不是她的错  对吗
It wasn't her fault, right?
至少去世不是她的错
The dying part, at least.
她希望你能节哀
She wanted you to have peace.
她就像是我的地图
She was like my map, you know.
只要我跟她说会儿话
She could always figure out where I was
她就能知道我怎么了  要去干什么
Or where I wanted to go just by talking to her.
甚至当我自认为是个另类时
Even when I felt like a freak,
她还能看着我  让我知道
She could look at me and I knew that
不管怎样  都会没事的
Everything was gonna be okay, no matter what.
我信任她
And I believed her.
可我连跟她说再见的机会都没有
I never got to say goodbye.
我能和她说说话吗
Can I talk to her?
她就在这儿
She's here.
你的爱给了她走出来的能量
She can feel your love. It's giving her strength.
我非常想你
I miss you so much.
我感觉很迷茫
I feel so lost.
现在谁来告诉我一切会好的
Who's gonna tell me that everything's gonna be okay now?
-你自己  -那正是她所想看到的
- You will. - That's what she wants.
你可以通过写小说把她留在你身边
You can keep her alive in everything that you write.
我为你自豪
I'm so proud of him.
她想告诉你  她为你自豪
And she wants you to know that she's proud of you.
告诉他对他爸爸好一点
Tell him to be kind to his father.
她说你爸爸是个好人
She's saying that your father's a good man.
只是他不敢再付出感情
He's just afraid of his heart.
他需要你告诉他如何去爱
And he needs to be taught how to love.
这太难了
It's so hard.
我明白
I know.
但值得一试
But it's worth it.
谢谢你
Thanks.
她在和你说再见
She's saying goodbye.
这么快
So soon?
时间到了
It's time.
再见  妈妈
Goodbye, Mom.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
没事  你呢
Yeah. You?
没事  我很好
Yeah. Yeah, really okay.
头痛消失了  感觉好多了
No more headaches. I feel much better.
只剩一件事没做
One more thing left to do.
我做不到  我没勇气给他
I can't. I can't give it to him.
妈  我对埃利斯做了件很蠢的事
Mom, I did a pretty stupid thing. This is about Ellis.
对  他跟你提过吗
Yeah. Did he mention it?
没
No.
我跟他说了对不起
I apologised to him,
我也想跟你说声对不起
And I'd like to apologise to you,
埃利斯来的时候  我像个混蛋一样
Because I've been kind of a jerk when it comes to Ellis.
只是像吗
Kind of?
好吧  我就是  完全发挥到极致的混蛋
A total, complete, you don't even wanna know, kind of jerk.
我要认为他应付不了  就不会带他来
I wouldn't have brought him if I thought he couldn't handle it.
什么  你知道...
Wait, wait. You knew that I was...
我的直觉告诉我  由着你们去
My instinct said just show up and let Ellis be Ellis and Jim be Jim,
你们会相处好的
And it'll all just sort itself out.
也许你会后悔"由着我"的
I think you might regret the "let Jim be Jim" part.
你知道我儿子在哪吗  我很担心他
Do you know where my son is? I'm worried about him. He hadn't...
他很好
He's okay now.
这是他给你的
This is for you.